<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Seth Russell</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Seth Russell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Seth Russell</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 02:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>About As an infomatician and experienced software engineer I help with the crucial effort of improving health care and reducing health care costs through the appropriate use of information technology. My experience and education provides me with the ability to develop requirements, build solutions, and test the success of a chosen solution. I have experience with commercial software such as Cerner Millennium Electronic Health Record (EHR) and Oracle Hyperion, standards based platforms such as SMART on FHIR and InfoButtons, and build from scratch tools and techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to profile your R code that calls C/C&#43;&#43; </title>
      <link>/2018/10/04/2018-10-04-how-to-profile-your-r-code-that-calls-c-c-plus-plus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/04/2018-10-04-how-to-profile-your-r-code-that-calls-c-c-plus-plus/</guid>
      <description>While there are many options for profiling C++ (or other compiled code) on Linux, many of those tools are difficult to get working correctly with R. Additionally, profiling R code with C++ is complicated due to different settings between various commonly use OSes. While there are some blog posts and presentation materials available on the Internet, many miss important steps that take some effort to determine the correct solution to resolve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kung Faux Pandas</title>
      <link>/project/kung-faux-pandas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/kung-faux-pandas/</guid>
      <description>There are many barriers to data access and data sharing, especially in the domain of machine learning on health care data. Legal constraints such as HIPAA protect patient privacy but slow access to data and limit reproducibility. Kung Faux Pandas is an end-to-end system called Kung Faux Pandas for easily generating de-identified or synthetic data which is statistically similar to given real data but lacks sensitive information. This system focuses on data synthesis and de-identification narrowed to a specific research question to allow for self-service data access without the complexities required to generate an entire population of data that is not needed for a given research project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example of Python data analysis</title>
      <link>/2018/09/27/2018-09-27-example-of-python-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/27/2018-09-27-example-of-python-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Work in Progress&amp;hellip;
This Analytics example is meant to demonstrate a few of the things you can do to analyze data stored in Google BigQuery using Python. Originally developed some time ago, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d clean it up and post it here.
For those that aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with BigQuery, it is a &amp;lsquo;serverless&amp;rsquo; database system that is fully managed and always available. Instead of charging per environment/instance/hour of time like many cloud database systems, Google charges based on the amount of data a query processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Package for Pediatric Complex Chronic Condition Classification</title>
      <link>/project/pediatric-complex-chronic-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pediatric-complex-chronic-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Version 2 of the Pediatric Complex Chronic Conditions (CCC) system was published &amp;ldquo;Pediatric complex chronic conditions classification system version 2: updated for ICD-10 and complex medical technology dependence and transplantation&amp;rdquo; by Chris Feudtner, James A Feinstein, Wenjun Zhong, Matt Hall and Dingwei Dai.
SAS and STATA scripts to generate CCC categories from ICD codes were provided by Feudtner et al. as an appendix to the above manuscript. However, those scripts can take many hours to run on large datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>