<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Seth Russell</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Seth Russell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Seth Russell</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kung Faux Pandas</title>
      <link>/project/kung-faux-pandas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/kung-faux-pandas/</guid>
      <description>There are many barriers to data access and data sharing, especially in the domain of machine learning on health care data. Legal constraints such as HIPAA protect patient privacy but slow access to data and limit reproducibility. Kung Faux Pandas is an end-to-end system called Kung Faux Pandas for easily generating de-identified or synthetic data which is statistically similar to given real data but lacks sensitive information. This system focuses on data synthesis and de-identification narrowed to a specific research question to allow for self-service data access without the complexities required to generate an entire population of data that is not needed for a given research project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Package for Pediatric Complex Chronic Condition Classification</title>
      <link>/project/pediatric-complex-chronic-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pediatric-complex-chronic-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Version 2 of the Pediatric Complex Chronic Conditions (CCC) system was published &amp;ldquo;Pediatric complex chronic conditions classification system version 2: updated for ICD-10 and complex medical technology dependence and transplantation&amp;rdquo; by Chris Feudtner, James A Feinstein, Wenjun Zhong, Matt Hall and Dingwei Dai.
SAS and STATA scripts to generate CCC categories from ICD codes were provided by Feudtner et al. as an appendix to the above manuscript. However, those scripts can take many hours to run on large datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>